# Fanyi Xiao

CONTACT Information 2078 Academic Surge University of California, Davis Davis, CA 95616, USA

Mobile: 949-491-2293 E-mail: fyxiao@ucdavis.edu

WWW: fanyix.cs.ucdavis.edu

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am broadly interested in computer vision and machine learning, with a focus on developing models to learn from videos. At a high level, my research interests can be categorized into three aspects: (i) Learning to understand videos. This includes developing algorithms for video recognition/detection/segmentation. (ii) Learning video representations with minimal human supervision (weakly and self-supervised learning from videos). (iii) Learning across modalities (e.g., image, video, language and audio).

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of California Davis, Computer Science Dept., Davis, CA, USA

Ph.D. candidate, Computer Science

• Advisor: Prof. Yong Jae Lee

## Carnegie Mellon University, Robotics Institute, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

M.S., Robotics, 2014

- Advisors: Prof. Martial Hebert and Prof. Yaser Sheikh
- Thesis: Model Recommendation for Large Scale Exemplar-based Object Detection

### Central South University, Computer Science Department, Changsha, China

B.S., Computer Science, 2012

• Thesis: Facial Expression Analysis with Active Appearance Model

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] Fanyi Xiao, Yong Jae Lee, Kristen Grauman, Jitendra Malik, and Christoph Feichtenhofer. Audiovisual SlowFast Networks for Video Recognition. 2019. (Under submission).
- [2] Daniel Bolya, Chong Zhou, **Fanyi Xiao**, and Yong Jae Lee. YOLACT++: Better Real-time Instance Segmentation. 2019. (Under submission).
- [3] Fanyi Xiao, Haotian Liu, and Yong Jae Lee. Identity from here, Pose from there: Self-supervised Disentanglement and Generation of Objects using Unlabeled Videos. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019.
- [4] Daniel Bolya, Chong Zhou, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee. YOLACT: Real-time Instance Segmentation. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019. (Oral presentation).
- [5] Xitong Yang, Xiaodong Yang, Ming-Yu Liu, Fanyi Xiao, Larry S Davis, and Jan Kautz. STEP: Spatio-Temporal Progressive Learning for Video Action Detection. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.
- [6] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Video Object Detection with an Aligned Spatial-Temporal Memory. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2018.
- [7] Wenjian Hu, Krishna Kumar Singh\*, Fanyi Xiao\*, Jinyoung Han, Chen-Nee Chuah, and Yong Jae Lee (\* equal contribution). Who Will Share My Image? Predicting the Content Diffusion Path in Online Social Networks. In ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM), 2018.

- [8] Fanyi Xiao, Leonid Sigal, and Yong Jae Lee. Weakly-supervised Visual Grounding of Phrases with Linguistic Structures. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2017.
- [9] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Track and Segment: An Iterative Unsupervised Approach for Video Object Proposals. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2016. (Spotlight presentation).
- [10] Krishna Singh, **Fanyi Xiao**, and Yong Jae Lee. Track and Transfer: Watching Videos to Simulate Strong Human Supervision for Weakly-Supervised Object Detection. In *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2016.
- [11] **Fanyi Xiao** and Yong Jae Lee. Discovering the Spatial Extent of Relative Attributes. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2015. (Oral presentation).
- [12] Fanyi Xiao and Martial Hebert. Efficient Model Evaluation with Bilinear Separation Model. In Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2015.
- [13] Zhiding Yu, Chunjing Xu, Deyu Meng, **Fanyi Xiao**, Wenbo Liu, and Jianzhuang Liu. Transitive Distance Clustering with K-Means Duality. In *International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2014.
- [14] Iljoo Baek, Taylor Stine, Denver Dash, Fanyi Xiao, Yaser Ajmal Sheikh, Yair Movshovitz-Attias, Mei Chen, Martial Hebert, and Takeo Kanade. Physical Querying with Multi-Modal Sensing. In Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2014.

AWARDS

- Most Innovative Award, COCO Object Detection Challenge, 2019
- Google Cloud Platform Research Grant, 2019
- Best Graduate Researcher Award, CS Dept. of UC Davis, 2018
- Azure Research Award, Microsoft, 2017
- Graduate Fellowship, UC Davis, 2015
- AWS Research Grant, Amazon Web Services, Inc., 2015
- Excellent Undergraduate Thesis, CSU, 2012
- Top Grade Scholarship (University-wide highest honor, 0.8%), CSU, 2010
- Sunward Scholarship (0.4%), Sunward Corporation, 2010
- 1st Grade Scholarship (6%), CSU, 2009
- National Scholarship (1%), Ministry of Education of China, 2009

#### EXPERIENCE

### Facebook AI Research (FAIR), Menlo Park, CA

Research Intern

June 2019 - Nov 2019

• An audiovisual video understanding architecture for recognition, detection and multi-modal self-supervised video representation learning. [Under submission]

### NVIDIA Research, Santa Clara, CA

Research Intern

July 2017 - Oct 2017

• An iterative action tube detection method for action detection. [CVPR 2019]

#### Disney Research, Pittsburgh, PA

Research Intern

June 2016 - Sept 2016

• Weakly supervised vision-language alignment (i.e., producing segmentation masks for free-form language inputs) by exploiting linguistic structure. [CVPR 2017]

SKILLS

• Programming: Python, C/C++, Lua, MATLAB, Java

• Misc: PyTorch, Torch7, Caffe, Caffe2, LINUX, LATEX

RELATED GRADUATE COURSES • CMU: Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Convex Optimization Math Fundamentals for Robotics / Learning-based Methods in Vision Mechanics of Manipulation

• UC Davis: Visual Recognition

SERVICE

- Reviewer, Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018-20
- Reviewer, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019
- Reviewer, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020
- Program Committee, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2019
- Program Committee, Intl. Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2020
- Reviewer, Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018
- Reviewer, Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2015-18